

SUMMARY

Enthusiastic Junior DevOps Engineer here, ready to dive into this field and work my way towards becoming a NetDevOps Engineer. I have hands-on experience with:

- CI/CD with GIT, Jenkins, kubernetes, and testing tools.
- Terraform and Ansible as IaC tools.
- Deploying Web apps on AWS cloud.
- Python programming and Bash scripting.

Hard skills

OS

Linux, Windows

Management & VCS & Databases

Ms Project, Trello, Git, MySQL

Virtualization/Cloud

VMware, KVM, Docker, Kubernetes, AWS

Scripting & Devops tools

Bash, Python, JAVA

Rest APIs, Ansible, Jenkins, Cucumber, karate, Terraform

Protocols

SSH, DNS, DHCP, FTP, NAT, DDNS, OpenVpn

Soft skills

Problem solving, Time management, Empathy, Teamwork, Adaptability

Languages

Arabe - Native

French - C

English-B2-Toeic 850

Interests

Sketching, Nature, Taekwondo

IMANE EL OUADI

DevOps Engineer

(+212) 681484536 – elouadi.imane@yahoo.com - Temara, Maroc







EXPERIENCE

June 2023 - November 2023 - Internship - SQLI, Rabat, Morocco

BDD testing using Karate and Cucumber

May 2023 - Ongoing - Training - ALX Morocco

Soft skills + AWS Cloud Practitioner & Solutions Architect Associate

May 2017 - SEP 2017 - Graduation Project - Wiibus - Sablons, France

Main Role: Deploying 4G routers on buses to provide passengers an onboard WiFi along with buses geolocation. Those are some accomplished missions:

- Assure routers onboarding with the right configuration, such as: Login page customization, User's authentication & sessions, Data usage, FTP logging and firewall settings.
- Routers Remote Management and server administration
- Company Website server provisioning
- Firmware upgrades, Clients support, Communication with the supplier.

MAY 2016 - SEP 2016 - industrial Project- Berthiez - Saint Étienne, France

A feasibility study of a vision system for a CNC tool changer using Matlab.

APR 2015 - Jun 2015 - Internship - ONCF - Rabat, Maroc

Cellular planning for the GSM-R railway network using Atoll.

EDUCATION & CERTIFICATES

Ocт 2023 - AWS Cloud Practitioner - G3P9WDJKXJFQQTSV

Feb 2024 - AWS SAA-C03 - 529808c3d0994029850979eec4e87154

2014 to 2017 - Master's degree – Embedded Systems and Telecoms - Telecom Saint-Étienne. France

2012 to 2014 - CPGE - Math and Physics - International University of Rabat

2012 Baccalaureate - Mathematics, Morocco

PROJECTS

- Deploying a dockerized web App using CI/CD Jenkins Pipeline ·
- Provisioning AWS resources using Terraform
- Conception of a 4-wheeled surveillance robot controlled via a web interface, utilizing a Raspberry Pi board
- Deploying a Microservice web application in AWS ECS.
- Automating the configuration of a network lab on GNS3 using Ansible